Today we are celebrating here,
今天我们在
in this Holy land,
这神圣的地方
the birthday of Shri Krishna.
庆祝克里希纳的寿辰
Shri Krishna is the ultimate,
我向你描述过
of the Fatherhood that I described to you before,
克里希纳是代表最终的父性
Who came on this earth,
他降生在这个地球上
and illustrated the ultimate of that.
阐释最终的父性
So on this earth the highest Fatherhood is,
地球上最终的父性是
Shri Krishna's awareness.
克里希纳的意识
But in the Kingdom of God, we can say in the,
在神的国度里，我们可以说
Heavens or even above everything else,
在天堂或甚至一切的最高处
resides Sadashiva who does not take incarnations.
有不曾降世的至高湿婆神
He is one of the aspects; Shri Krishna
他的其中一个形相--至高湿婆神
is one of the aspects of Sadashiva which is the Father.
作为父亲的其中一个形相 是克里希纳
And the Adi Shakti or the Holy Ghost
而太初之母或圣灵
is the other aspect of Sadashiva which is His Power.
则是至高湿婆神的 另一个力量的形相
So when Shri Krishna incarnated on this earth,
当克里希纳降世之际
an aspect of this Adi Shakti
太初之母
came on this earth as Radha.
以罗陀的形相降世
She's the same who came as the Mother of Christ,
她也以基督的母亲这个形相降世
and She gave the name of Christ,
她为基督命名
as the surname of Shri Krishna,
基督的别名是克里希纳
as if it's Shri Krishna's name Krishna, from Krishna.
就如锡吕‧克里希纳的名字 是克里希纳 源自克里希纳(krishna)
He's called as Krist in Indian languages - Krist.
印度语称呼他为Krist
And I have told you before why He was called as Jesu or Yesu.
我告诉过你们为何 称他为Jesu或Yesu
So today we are going to see to the two aspects of Shri Krishna,
今天我们就要看看 克里希纳的两个形相
which were the manifestation of His Divine birth.
那是他神圣出生的彰显
In Rama's life they showed a man,
罗摩的一生展现一个 Purushottama的人
a purushottama the best of the Father in worldly affairs.
即俗世最佳的父亲
And in Shri Krishna's life they showed Him,
克里希纳的一生展现
the highest Fatherhood as in Yogeshwara
他是Yogeshwara(瑜伽之主)
or in Divine world.
或上天世界的最高的父性
So the first aspect of Krishna we have to understand
因此，我们最先要明白的 克里希纳形相
is the Yogeshwara,
是Yogeshwara
and the second aspect of Him as the Virata.
其二是要明白他作为 宇宙大我(Virata)的形相
Yogeshwara means the Lord of the Yoga,
Yogeshwars意思是瑜伽之主
or the power of Yoga.
或瑜伽的力量
He is called because He reached the,
这样称呼他是因为他已经到达
optimum that one has to reach as a yogi.
作为瑜伽士最理想的位置
As if He's the ideal that you have to reach.
他是你要到达的最完美的目标
Now as a Yogi He was born of a royal family
作为瑜伽士，他生于王族
but He lived in the jungles, in the forest,
却住在丛林里，森林里
with the cows, with ordinary people.
与牛只和普通人为伍
He used to sleep on the ordinary places
当他放牧时，通常都是
like sometimes on the stone or on the grass
睡在普通的地方
when He would go with His cows for their feeding.
如石头上或草地上
Secondly He was very, very aware,
其二，他完全知道
absolutely aware of His powers, without any Ego.
自己的力量，毫无自我
He had a special power called samharashakti
他拥有一种被称为samharashakti的特别力量
by which He could destroy all those people
他能运用这种力量摧毁
who tried to harm the Divine manifestation.
任何想破坏上天显现的人
The samharashakti is expressed
Samharashakti显现为
as the chakra in His hand.
他手上的轮穴
And another is the gada in His Hand.
另一种力量是他手上的锤矛(gada)
These powers were within Him and,
这些力量都在他内里建构好
He acted according to the power of Radha
他按照罗陀的力量行事
because She was the One
因为罗陀是
who sustained the power of Shri Krishna.
克里希纳的力量的持守者
The proof of that is this, that
这种说法的证据就是
when He was in Gokul with Radha He did all his
当他与罗陀在Gokul
samhara, work samharakarya
他做他的Samhara，samharakarya
and afterwards He just became a sarti
之后，他只当sarti(萨蒂)
- is a chariot driver for Arjuna.
即亚周那的车夫
So for His disciple Arjuna He became even a chariot driver.
在他的门徒亚周那面前 他只是个车夫
The another great quality of Yogeshwara was
瑜伽之主的另一个 了不起的品质是
the complete discretion power built in.
辨别能力 这种质量他内在已经拥有
So He knew who was a devil and who was not,
因此他知道谁是魔鬼谁不是
who is good, who is bad;
谁是好人谁不是
who is possessed, who is not possessed;
谁被鬼附着谁没有
who is innocent who is not.
谁是纯真谁不是
This was built in within Him, this power,
这些品质都建构在他内在
of complete discrimination.
内在的辨别能力
And He had a capacity,
他另一种能力更能表达
more expressing His witness hood, as a sakshi.
他作为sakshi的旁观见证能力
He had a capacity, I mean He was a sakshi Himself.
他拥有一种能力 我是说他本身就是sakshi
l should say this way is easier to understand.
这样说令你更容易明白
He was a sakshi means He had the capacity
他是sakshi的意思是他有能力
of witnessing the whole world as a play.
旁观这个世界为一出戏剧
At the time of Rama, Rama was,
在罗摩的时代
the one who got involved into His problems,
为了向人类显示他是人类
to show as if He is a full human being.
罗摩让自己受自己的问题缠绕
So that human should not say that He was God
那么人类就不会说他是神
so how could we accept God
不管如何，我们又怎能接受神
because He was God after all.
因为他是神
Now this capacity in Him to witness,
他这种旁观见证能力
has to be seen in every yogi.
必须能在每个瑜伽士身上出现
The element He controls is ether.
他控制的元素是以太
We call it as akasha in Sanskrit.
梵文称以太为akasha
This ether as you know we are using now
你也知道，我们今天都把以太元素
for our television, for our radio,
运用在电视、收音机
for every sort of a collective work.
各式各样集体工作上
So we have to be
作为瑜伽士
in charge of the ether element, as yogis.
我们要控制以太
And that is the subtlest of all, in the sense that,
某程度上，这是精微中的精微
you permeate into everything with that.
你透过以太渗透入一切
And is above all, like plastic also permeates into everything
它是高于一切 就如塑料也渗透进一切
into matter, into everything up to the air.
一切物质，一切直至空中的物质
But it cannot enter into ether.
但它不能进入以太
So the negativity cannot enter into ether.
负面能量不能进入以太
So when you enter into your ethereal zone,
一旦你进入上天的领域
you actually enter into the area,
实际上，你进入的领域是
which is thoughtless awareness.
无思虑的意识里
So to achieve your ethereal state
所以要到达上天的层次
you have to expand your thoughtless awareness.
你要扩展你的无思无虑 的知觉状态
And the sustenance of that is done by Christ, by the Spirit.
持守这种状态的是基督，是灵
So you can realize now as a yogi,
你能意识到作为瑜伽士
your state of mind should be ethereal.
你的心境(state of mind) 要处于上天的层次
And what should be the state of your superego
你该处于何种状态，超我
- this is the ego part of it that
你的自我要处于
you should be in ethereal state -
上天的状态
and as a superego you should see it as a play.
作为超我，你应把一切看作一出戏
You should see the play of the negative.
要看到负面力量的戏剧在上演
Negativity will run away but don't get involved into it,
负面力量会跑掉 你不要牵涉入内
play into their hands,
不要受负面力量愚弄
then the negativity will separate from you.
那么负面力量便会离你而去
So the ego and superego both rise from the visshuddhi chakra.
自我和超我都会从喉轮升起
They can be receded by the agnya chakra
从额轮退下
but are to be sucked in the visshuddhi.
被喉轮吸走
The greatest quality of Yogeshwara is that
瑜伽之主最了不起的品质是
He is not at all involved into anything,
他完全不牵涉入内
detached absolutely.
完全不执着依恋
If He eats His food He does not eat it,
若他进食，不是在进食
if He speaks He does not speak,
若他说话，不是在说话
if He sees He does not see,
若他看，不是在看
if He hears He does not hear.
若他听，不是在听
It has no effect on Him, no retention on it,
这些事情一丝一毫都不影响他 也不会在他身上停留
no action on it.
亦对他不起作用
Whatever He is He is complete.
不管如何，他是完全圆满的
Sixteen petals is complete mould,
十六片花瓣是完整的模子
sixteenth day of the moon is the Purnima is the.
第十六天是月圆的日子
That is how one has to be, complete in oneself,
我们就是要这样，自我完善
complete confidence in oneself.
对自己有绝对的信心
But the confidence should not be confused with ego.
信心不应与自我混淆
But confidence is complete wisdom, is complete dharma.
信心是智慧，是正法(dharma)
It is complete love, complete beauty,
是爱，是美丽
and is complete God.
也是神
That's what it should be.
就是要这样
Now when He said that you give up
在薄伽梵歌，当他说
all your dharmas and surrender to me in Gita
你要放弃正法，顺服委身于我
what He was meaning -
他是说
that all other things about which you are worried you give up
你要放开所有担忧
and become, one with me so I look after you.
与我合一，那么我便会照顾你
Give up the responsibility to Shri Krishna.
把担子交给克里希纳
So the complete integrated Divinity
那么与上天完全的整合便会
will start expressing through you.
透过你表达出来
Means if you say that you have to be responsible,
意思是若你说要自己来做
then He says: 'All right go ahead, try.'
他便会说，好吧 你做吧，试试看
But if you say, that you are responsible,
但若你说，你要担起责任
I am just an institution or an instrument in Your hand,
我只是你手上的机构 或你手上的工具
then, you start manifesting it well,
那么你便能好好的彰显它
and that is how your visshuddhi chakra gets opened out.
你的喉轮就是这样得到开启
This is some part of the Yogeshwara l have spoken to you.
这是我告诉过你 瑜伽之主的部分素质
But as He is the brain within us,
因为他是脑袋，在我们内里
He becomes the brain within us.
他变成我们内在的脑袋
We have to know all the qualities of a Divine brain,
我们要知道他俱备神圣脑袋的
are with Him.
所有品质
So whatever we do with our brain,
不管我们怎样运用脑袋
like intrigue, thieving,
如策划阴谋，盗窃
the deception,
欺骗
all which are bad things by your brain as they call it,
所有人们称的坏事
are done by Him for the Divine purpose,
都是他以神圣之名而做的
without getting any blemish upon Himself.
但这些事情却没有在他 身上留下任何瑕疵污点
And the other side of it whatever we do,
另一方面，不管我们做了什么
so called positive, like politics or like diplomacy,
那些所谓正面的事情 如政治，外交
like leadership,
领导
all that is,
全都是他做的
His Own doing, like even the thinking,
即使是思考未来
of the future and all that He does for us
一切他为我们做的
- planning, thinking all those things, administration -
计划，想着这些事情，管理
as a play, everything is done as a play,
as a play, everything is done as a play 就如戏剧，一切事情都是一出戏
because He is the Master, as we call as a sutradara
因为他是主人 就如我们称呼为sutradara的事情
the one who does the prologue in a drama
即一出戏演开场的那个演员
the one who plays with the strings, with the pantomimes.
调教弦线的乐师、演哑剧的演员
Now the other thing that we have to understand,
现在，另一件我们要明白的事情
Shri Krishna at this stage of Sahaja Yoga,
是克里希纳在霎哈嘉瑜伽这个阶段
that it is the Virata Shakti that is manifesting at this time,
即宇宙大我显现的时代
and not the Shri Krishna Shakti which was at His time.
不是克里希纳力量显现的时代
And the power that is working here is no more
现在正在运作的力量不再是
that of Radha, or of Mary, but of Viratangana.
来自罗陀，或来自玛利亚 而是来自Viratangana
That's why the knowledge of Sahaja Yogis is,
这就是为何霎哈嘉瑜伽士 拥有的知识
much wider,
比任何时代的圣人
than the knowledge of all the Saints, of ages.
更为广阔
But is not deeper than them.
虽然广阔却没有他们那么深层
If you can deepen your knowledge,
若你能深化你的知识
this wider knowledge will have proper roots within you.
这广阔的知识便能 在你内在好好扎根
So the brain are the roots,
脑袋是根
here are the roots of the whole, tree of life.
是整棵生命之树的根
Actually Kundalini comes up and waters the brain first
实际上，灵量升起 脑袋先得到灌溉
so that the whole tree of life is
让整棵生命之树
drenched in the Divine bliss, and Divine knowledge.
受上天的祝福 上天的知识所滋润湿透
So this Virata Shakti that we have to work out
我们要成就的宇宙大我力量
gives us the sense of collective consciousness first.
首先给我们集体意识
First we understand it through our brainpower.
我们首先透过脑力明白它
But the whole brainpower is to be guided by the heart.
整个脑力是受心所指引
Is to be, watered
要受心所灌溉
but in Sanskrit is a very beautiful word sinchena -
梵文灌溉是个美丽的字--sinchena
like dewdrops you see, sprayed with the love of God.
像露水，以神的爱来喷洒
So the integration of this brain
所以脑袋要
has to take with heart and with your liver.
与心脏和肝脏整合
Then only the Virata Shakti takes another form.
宇宙大我力量只有采用另一个形相
The weapons of killing, become the weapons of forgiveness.
杀戮的武器变为宽恕武器
Every sort of destructive power is used for the construction,
每一种毁灭的力量都运用在建设上
as if it is tricked,
就像这是个把戏
like now I told them a trick how to trick these gurus.
如我现在告诉他们 怎样戏弄这些导师
The power that they have can be tricked against them
他们拥有的力量能愚弄他们
as He said that their teeth must be put into their necks,
如他说他们的牙齿必须放在颈项
into their throats.
放在喉咙
instead of taking out their teeth
最好是不要拔掉牙齿
better put them back into their own throats.
而是把它们放回喉咙里
And if you can do that, then there is no problem,
若你能做到，就没问题了
as far as their effect on us is concerned
就影响力而言
because you are more powerful and more tricky.
你是更有力量，更足智多谋
Because the Virata Shakti has now taken that form.
因为宇宙大我力量 现在已经采用这个形相
Like the tree when it grows it grows upward,
就如树木是向上生长
but when it is laden with fruit it comes down.
一旦它结满果实，便会垂下来
First it is attractive by its flowers, by its timber,
树的花朵，树的木材
by its all other parts of its body.
树的各个部分先吸引人注意
And people try to destroy it for it.
人们因此想破坏它
But when the fruits appear they want to preserve it,
但当树结出果子，他们便想保育树
and the tree bends down, its humility is very valuable.
树垂下来，它的谦卑是很有价值
So you are the fruits,
你就是果实
that Viratangana Shakti, you are the fruits.
Viratangana力量，你是果实
Because you are so valuable,
因为你是那么有价值
that those people who wanted to ruin
那些想摧毁，想破坏
or to destroy the Divine power from this earth
这个地球神圣力量的人
will start thinking that
会开始想
they have to gain something out of these fruits.
从果实中得到一点好处
So today the Virata Shakti has given you a great value,
今天宇宙大我力量 已经给你了不起的价值
because people see that by having
因为能与霎哈嘉瑜伽士一起
one Sahaja Yogi with them it is so precious.
是被视为很珍贵的
Say one ordinary man gets his Realization,
就如普通人得到自觉
then he develops his value,
他便发展了他的价值
in that - his own value, he can be respected, loved
他自己的价值 若他是个称职的霎哈嘉瑜伽士
and given the highest, if he's a proper Sahaja Yogi.
他便能得到尊重，得到爱 被赐予最高的位置
So you should understand today that Virata Shakti is-
所以今天你要明白 宇宙大我力量是
we are going to worship that Virata Shakti
我们要敬拜给我们果实的
which has given fruits.
宇宙大我力量
As a result of that all these different churches
因此，不同的教堂
and fanaticism and atheism, and communism
狂热主义、无神论、共产主义和
and all that 'ism' - all these will neutralize
一切的"主义" 所有这些都会被中和
because they will see they've benefited it.
因为他们会知道他们对它有益
But you have to become that,
你就是要变成这样
that is the biggest thing one has to know
我们最重要是要知道
is to bend down towards the Mother Earth,
要向大地之母垂下
to be humble.
要谦虚
Absolutely the humility inside out,
从内而外的绝对的谦虚
is really going to give you
这样才能真正给你
the complete value of Sahaja Yoga fruits.
霎哈嘉瑜伽果实的完全价值
Those Sahaja Yogis who boast about themselves
夸耀自己的霎哈嘉瑜伽士
are like the fruits which are getting ruined
就像在树上烂掉的果实
only on the tree.
只有垂下来的果实
The only fruits which bend down
才会被接受为
are accepted as good and matured fruits
好的，成熟的果实
and not those who assert that they are the highest.
而不是自称位处最高的果实
But some of the negative people
负面的人完全不要
should not by any chance take advantage of this,
从中取利
and say that, they are good
说，他们那么好
because they are bending down, it's not the logic.
是因为他们垂下，不是这种逻辑
Some of them boast they are humble,
一些人吹嘘自己很谦虚
even a rotten fruit bends down.
烂掉的果实也垂下来
But the matured fruit,
但成熟的果实
shows its humility by its weight.
却以它的重量来展示它的谦虚
That is the Guru tattwa, weight.
这是导师原则，重量
So from the Viratangana power,
所以从Viratangana力量
we get the power of maturity up to the fruit
我们取得达至果实成熟的力量
and then we become blessed by Guru Principle.
接着，我们得到导师原则的福佑
Those who are still involved,
仍想得到
in getting to better sunshine,
更好的阳光
or getting to better water supply,
更好的水
or all these things are not yet matured
或有类似要求的人，仍未成熟
because the fruit doesn't need anything anymore.
因为果实不再有任何需求
It doesn't need anything from the Mother Earth,
它不再对大地之母或
nor from the elements.
任何元素有任何需求
But it surrenders, it bends, it bows to the Mother Earth.
它只是顺服，它垂下 向大地之母鞠躬
So the Sahaja Yogi who goes on asking questions to Mother,
不停向母亲发问
bringing personal problems, stupid ideas, negativity,
向母亲提出很多个人问题 愚蠢的、负面的想法的人
all those people are still not yet the fruits.
仍未是果实
But the matured people are those who surrender,
成熟的人是向大地之母
who bow to the Mother Earth.
顺服委身、鞠躬的人
So the capacity to bow is the best judgment of yourself;
所以有能力鞠躬的人 是最佳评价自己的方法
and leaving everything,
把一切交托
to the power of gravity of Your Mother
母亲的重力
to do every work for you;
让母亲为你做一切
and leaving all your small little worries behind.
把你小小的忧虑抛之脑后
You have to rise above, these restricting powers.
你必须超越这些限制的力量
And achieve the completion of this Virata Shakti,
成就这个宇宙大我的力量
which ultimately becomes a madhura Shakti,
这力量最终成为madhura力量
madhura. There's no word in English language
madhura这个字没有英语能解释它
but it means a sweet power.
它解作甜美的力量
Like the fruit becomes sweet,
像果实变甜
that's how you all have to become very sweet.
就像你们全都变得非常甜美
Krishna tried to make everything very sweet in the sense
克里希纳想把一切都变得甜美
it was all madhura shakti that was acting,
某程度上全是madhura力量在起作用
all His play, all His dancing,
你读到他的一切戏剧
all His stories if you read
一切舞蹈，一切故事
is nothing but madhura shakti
全都是madhura力量
- towards gopas and gopis,
为众牧女和
towards other Sahaja Yogis.
霎哈嘉瑜伽士而演出
So you have to keep your Mother pleased
你要透过取悦霎哈嘉瑜伽士
by pleasing all other Sahaja Yogis,
以取悦你的母亲
and not other people, they are not important.
而不是取悦其他人，他们不重要
So today we are going to shorten the Puja
今天我们要缩短崇拜
and that's why it took so much time upstairs to shorten it.
所以要花那么多时间走往楼上
So the time lost is time gained forever and ever.
失去的时间是永永远远得到的时间
May God bless you all.
愿神祝福你们